http://www.antaisce.org/publications/privacy-statement

Privacy Statement - The National Trust for Ireland - An Taisce
2018Introduction
An Taisce takes the privacy of its members, subscribers and users very seriously and takes great care with the information we obtain. This Privacy Statement outlines how personal information is collected, used and protected as part of the terms and conditions of this website.
It complies with the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003 (as amended or superseded, including from 25 May 2018 the General Data Protection Regulation) and other related legislation.
We recommend that if you submit your personal data via this site, you check this page regularly to ensure you are happy with any subsequent updates.
An Taisce is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Privacy Statement applies to the An Taisce website and governs data collection and usage. By using the An Taisce website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.
Security of your Personal Information
An Taisce secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. An Taisce secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.
Changes to this Statement
An Taisce will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and user feedback. An Taisce encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how An Taisce is protecting your information.
Third parties
You are able to access third party sites through links on our website. The An Taisce is not responsible for and makes no representations concerning the condition of and content of, or products offered at the third party site or their commitment to Privacy Laws. Any link from the An Taisce’s website does not indicate, expressly or impliedly, that An Taisce endorses the site or the products or services offered there.
If you access a third party site, it is at your own risk. It is recommended you check the terms and conditions and privacy policies of the sites you visit independently.
The An Taisce uses third-party online services to collect, store, process and/or protect information, such as Google, SurveyMonkey, Realex, SmartSheet, PayPal, graphic designer, software developers, and printers. We may also share your data with our professional advisers and auditors. Access to these sites is strictly confidential and restricted to the data processor and controllers.
An Taisce makes every reasonable endeavour to ensure these sites, along with Facebook, Instagram and Twitter, and third-party vendor contracts to meet the GDPR's requirements.
What personal information will we collect from you?
We will only collect enough personal data from you to provide you with the service you have requested.
If you sign up to our mailing service, we will ask for your email address as a requisite. The form will also collect your IP address, and timestamp associated with anyone who submits the form. You can provide your name, county, job title, and institution, for monitoring and reporting purposes (the information will be anonymised) and for tailored emails, but this is optional.
We will also hold information you have supplied for other purposes – for example in connection with enquiries made via our contact form. By submitting information to us you are consenting to the management and use of your information as set out in this Privacy Statement.
For An Taisce Membership we may collect: Name, Organisation and Position, Address, Email, Phone, Default Payment Method, Membership Type, Date of Joining. For Family Memberships we may collect the same data for an additional family member. If you pay by Direct Debit we will collect and securely store bank account number and signature. If you donate over €250 in a year we may write to you to give you an opportunity to fill in a CHY form for An Taisce to claim back income tax paid on your donations. If you complete this form we will securely store your PPS number. If you pay by credit card online your transaction is processed by Paypal and we do not collect your credit card details. If you pay by credit or debit card by post or by phone then we collect your credit or debit card details. We process these promptly using Realex and then immediately securely erase the credit card details.
What do we do with your personal information?
We will use your information to administer your membership. This includes submitting your membership to An Taisce's Council for approval, processing your payment, sending your Membership card, making your name and membership status available to An Taisce's Local Associations, sending you An Taisce's Annual Report and agendas for General Meetings of the company.
If you supply your information for other purposes, for example if you send us an enquiry, we will only use your information for the purpose of answering your query.
If we want to use your data for any purpose outside of the terms of this Privacy Statement, we will ask you first.
Marketing and News
When you become a member, we will invite you to opt in to receiving news. If you opt in we will use your personal information to send you emails with information on events, news, continued professional development, and career opportunities which may be of interest to you. You can opt out of news emails using an unsubscribe link in the emails we send.
An Taisce does not sell, rent or lease its mailing list or membership lists to third parties.
Membership of An Taisce - The National Trust for Ireland, a Company Limited by Guarantee.
An Taisce - The National Trust for Ireland is a Company Limited by Guarantee. When you join An Taisce as a member you become a member or shareholder or this Company Limited by Guarantee.
Membership of An Taisce is governed by An Taisce's Memorandum and Articles of Association. Note that clause VIII of the Memorandum states:
Every member of An Taisce undertakes to contribute to the assets of An Taisce in the event of its being wound up while he/she is a Member or within one year afterwards, for payment of the debts and liabilities of An Taisce contracted before he/she ceases to be a Member and of the costs, charges and expenses of winding up, and for the adjustment of the rights of the contributories amongst themselves, such amount as may be required, not exceeding €6.35.
Note that under under the Companies Acts any member of the public may by appointment visit the registered office of the company and inspect the register of members. In this case, only names and surnames would be included in the register of members.
How long will we keep your information?
An Taisce will keep your information for up to seven years after you actively discontinue your
membership. It will additionally monitor activity reports on our server and delete information on subscribers that show no activity for a sustained length of time (no less than two years, no more than seven years).
Disclosure of personal information
Your personal information will be disclosed only to relevant representatives of An Taisce, companies or persons specifically contracted to manage data for An Taisce in accordance with its instructions (see third-party site information), and if there is a legal obligation to do so.
Only necessary information is disclosed where an obligation in law exists.
All reasonable steps are taken to ensure all information is accurate, complete and up to date. If your circumstances change, please let us know.
Security of your personal information
We are committed to ensuring your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.
We take appropriate steps to protect all of your personal information we hold from misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. This protection applies in relation to information stored in both electronic and hard copy form.
An Taisce will never sell any of you data
IP Addresses
Every time you connect to our website, we store web server logs which show your unique IP address. This identifies what you have looked at; whether the page request was successful or not; and which browser you used to view the pages. This data will only be used for statistical purposes and helps to inform us about the usage of the site and how many hits we receive.
There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by An Taisce. This information can include: browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by An Taisce for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the An Taisce website.
Cookies
The An Taisce website uses cookies to understand how you access and use this site, and collect anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you. The information gathered in this way is anonymous and cannot be linked to you personally.
Cookies can also be used to enable a transaction, such as with Paypal. We use this data to inform the development of our services, user experience and in creating new content.
An Taisce has additionally implemented Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. This uses cookies to gather website visitor data, such as age, gender, and interests. We use information to identify the key interests and demographics of our users, in order to optimise website content and improve user experience. This data remains anonymous; no personally identifiable information is collected. Google may use the data collected to contextualise and personalise the ads of its own advertising network. You are able to opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising at any time.
Your Rights
Right to be Informed
This Privacy Statement informs you about your data.
Right of Access
Each year when we send you a renewal letter and/or membership card we include a form on the reverse which lists the data we hold on you. You can write to us at any other time and we will supply this too.
Right of Rectification
On the reverse of the renewal letters and membership card letters that we send we include a form listing the data we hold on you and invite you to make corrections. You can also write to us at any time to make a correction. We will reply to you within 30 working days.
Right or Erasure
See the Retention Policy section of this Privacy Statement for details of how and when we will generally erase your data. You can write to us to request that we delete all your data. We will review this request and communicate the result to you. We will erase as much data as possible but may need to retain certain data for a period, for example financial records in case of audit.
Right to Restrict Processing
If you are opted in to news emails you can write to us to opt out of these.
Right to Data Portability
We can provide you with a statement of your membership payments on request.
Right to Object
Contact us at membership@antaisce.org to make a complaint about your data.
How can I find out more?
Further information on your data privacy rights is available on the website of the Data Protection Commissioner www.dataprotection.ie
Revisions
23rd May 2018: Privacy Statment complete re-written for GDPR compliance.
2020 An Taisce - The National Trust for Ireland, Tailors' Hall, Back Lane, Dublin, D08 X2A3, Ireland. +353 1 454 1786 - info@antaisce.org
Registered in Ireland 12469 - Charity No. CHY4741 - Charity Regulator No. 20006358 - EU Transparency Register No 473905437651-60.
Please note that this website uses cookies. If you continue to navigate this website, you are agreeing to their use.
